Guide to the Bloodroot Collective Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Bloodroot Collective, 1957-2010; Series I; 5.75
  - Miriam, Selma, personal files
    - Biographical
      - Oral histories, 2009-2010
        - Oral history, 2009; 1
          Conducted by Kristin Baxivanos on August 21, 2009. Miriam discusses her early life, education at Tufts, marriage, motherhood, feminism, the women's movement, the Bloodroot Collective, coming out, and feminist thinkers (Mary Daly, Sheila Jeffreys, and Catherine MacKinnon).
          - Use copy, Computer file (MP3)
        - Oral history, 2010 April 7; 1
          Conducted by Mary Caldera on April 7, 2010. Miriam discusses her early life, education at Tufts, marriage, motherhood, feminism, the women's movement, the Bloodroot Collective, and coming out.
- Bloodroot Restaurant and Bookstore, 1969-2009; Series II; 2.25 linear feet
  Series II is arranged by type of material and alphabetically therein.
  The series documents the Bloodroot restaurant and bookstore. The series consists of administrative correspondence and financial records, publicity and advertising material, and resource files, which contain small press and ephemeral items on various feminist topics sold by and of interest to the Collective.
  - General
    - Anomaly Press, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Bloodroot Feminist Bookstore, 1977-1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1996 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Restaurant license, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Sanguinaria Press, 1978-1985 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Financial Records
    - Ledger, 1978-1990 (Box 8, Folder 6-28)
    - Ledger, 1989-2000 (Box 9, Folder 1-15)
  - Publicity and Advertising
    - Event publicity, 1977-1997 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Reviews, 1976-2009 (Box 10, Folder 2-5)
      - Oversize, 1977 (Box 13A, Folder 4)
  - Resource Files
    Topical materials sold at Bloodroot Feminist Bookstore or collected by Bloodroot collective members. The material consists of flyers, copies of essays, booklets, and other small publications documenting subjects of interest to the Collective, such as feminism, women's health and women's rights.
    - Abortion, 1979 and undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Book and periodical list, 1977-1982 and undated (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
    - Bread and Roses, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Dancing in the Kitchen, Undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Fat liberation, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Feminist theory, Circa 1970s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Fireweed Quarterly, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Gynecological health, Circa 1970s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Oversize, 1977 (Box 13A, Folder 5)
    - Inland Book Company, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - International women's movements, 1977 and undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Law and legislation, Circa 1970s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - L'evidente Lesbienne, 1984-1986 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Macrobiotics, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Maine Lesbian Feminist Newsletter, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Maize Lesbian Country Magazine, 1983-1987 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Matrices Newsletter, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Lesbian and gay, 1975 and undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Menopause, 1974-1980 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Mental health, 1969 and undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Minority women, 1969-1980 and undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Mothers, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Oversize, 1980 (Box 13A, Folder 6)
    - Pornography, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Rhode Island Feminist Theater Company, playbills and scripts, 1973 and undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - San Francisco Plexus, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - The Tongue, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Valley Women's Vengeance, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Van Deur, Kady, 1989-2003 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Vegetarianism, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - War and justice, Circa 1970s (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - The Waterfall, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Womanspirit, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Womanswork Connection, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Women in Distribution, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Women Library Workers Journal, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Women's events, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 11)